

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211













Total Experience: 22 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Electronics]

CSM Manager-Software Development Engineering seeking roles in Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Oracle ERP, SQL, PL/SQL, Informatica, Java, Jira, Git

Current Designation: Software Development Manager

Current Company: Cisco Systems (India) Private Limited

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Manager-Software Development, Program Manager, Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Oracle

ERP,SQL,PL/SQL,Informatica,Java,Jira,Git Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

2+ decades of experience; contributed to the business and technology vision and direction by influencing strategies and monitoring execution of major technology initiatives

Developed & supported complex and critical Enterprise Business Systems using Oracle ERP/CRM and Cloud based

Contributed in strategy development, thought leadership & implementation, business & operational transformation execution, business solution delivery, and business development

Led the development & execution of Technology Roadmaps / Transformations in alignment with Business Transformations and Enterprise IT Strategy without impacting business continuity

Spearheaded large-scale, complex programs through aggressive governance processes; developed relationships with business stakeholders / leadership teams across geographies and departments; presented changes, issues, risks and contingency plans to Portfolio Steering Committees to balance project resources, schedules and scope

Work Experience

- Cisco Systems (India) Private Limited as Software Development Manager Dec 2020 to Till Date
- Cisco Systems India (Pvt.) Ltd., as Manager -Software Development Engineering Jan 2005 to Jun 2020

Delivered large-scale, complex programs with a focus on technology transformation; collaborated with leadership teams to evaluate technology challenges

Built & led high-performing & motivated team from scratch; constructed SME strength in technology/functional domain Supervised Channel Partner Delivery Portfolio (\$11M) with agility and on-time delivery with right prioritization, engineering methodologies and resource strategy

Structured Audit & Control Framework to improve operational efficiencies through proactive data validation and alert mechanism which resulted in critical issue prevention

Improved user experience and slashed maintenance costs through application rationalization & consolidation Cultivated Engineering & Operational Best Practices; implemented shift-left strategy that resulted in 10% defect density during QA phase and 90% phase containment; reduced QA cycle time by 25%

Established best practices & governance structure to meet the quality, security & life cycle compliance standards of the enterprise

Enabled scale & agility in delivering business capabilities through management of 130+ multiple vendor organization resources, SOW process, and resource strategy & optimization

Aug'12-Nov'14: Program Manager (Customer Care IT Organization)

Led Cisco Service Contracts & installed base domain and created program delivery roadmap in collaboration with IT & business stakeholders

Defined program structure & governance to align deliverables with enterprise release schedules/guidelines Drove project management best practices and quality standards to meet consistent outcomes across the portfolio

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Prepared program risk & mitigation document and facilitated weekly communications to stakeholders

Set up IT delivery change management process; championed strategic initiatives to achieve delivery excellence Optimized resources across projects, drove productivity with resource strategy, aligned team's strengths with the organization priorities; conceptualized and steered Fresh grad training program which reduced ramp up time from 12 to 3 months

Facilitated functional brown bags, active mentoring by analysts to improve business acumen of Service Contracts Management team, resulted in technical architecture consolidation proposals for contract management applications Established governance process in adherence with engineering best practices to achieve engineering excellence and delivery agility which resulted in nil postproduction critical issues due to release and smooth normalization periods; planned & implemented traceability matrix to prevent requirement gaps

Blueprinted Resource Strategy to drive the accountability at service asset level to improve SME knowledge, phase containment metrics (90%) and single digit defects during QA

Strategized service rollback plans for customer care org in partnership with key stakeholders to minimize the business impact in case of issues during releases

Dec'06-Jul'12: Project Manager (Customer Commerce IT Organization)

Delivered various projects using global workforce to support commerce initiatives and service sales optimization functions

Improved Installed Base Service Agreements Data Quality (IBSAVE), RMA update Process, Customer and Partner abilities to manage contracts and contract health report to reduce quoting validation issues

Jan'05-Nov06: Tech Lead

Worked in the Installed Base, Service Agreements Domain

Built the team from scratch and successfully started & operationalized the offshore engagement in India
Designed search service, data validation & governance process to improve data quality of Installed Base data attributes
Enabled users with contract management operations and improved RMA interface

Specsoft Consulting Inc

Dec 2000 to Dec 2004

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Electronics) from Nagarjuna University in 1992

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Electronics) from Nagarjuna University in 1995

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Certified Scrum Master Proact Business Transformation Certification Managing Projects Scheduling & Cost Control

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Oracle ERP			
SQL & PL/SQL			
Informatica			
SNOWFLAKE			
JAVA			
JIRA & RALLY			
Microsoft Project			
GIT & Jenkins			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.